Anurag Kumar Singh

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER · https://www.linkedin.com/in/anurag27k/ anurag27k@gmail.com · +919445682075

SUMMARY

Anurag is a result oriented and senior product designer with 6+ years of expertise spanning various sectors, including Demand supply management, Healthcare, ERP and Government permitting and licensing. Demonstrated proficiency in design and coding, with a track record of handling complex projects with success. Integrates technical skills with a strong aesthetic sense. He has led teams to harness success and create a culture of constant improvement while contributing to the design community. He has a record of driving projects from 0 to 1 while working on multiple work streams in parallel. He is a proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

SKILLS

Core Skills:

UX Design & Research · UI Design · Interaction Design · Web Development · Testing & Evaluation · User Centered Design · Data Visualization · Service Design · Accessibility · Mixed media · Augmented Reality · Virtual Reality · Graphic Design · Color Theory · Typography · Layout Design

Soft/business Skills:

Leadership and Team Management · Design Strategy and Conceptualization · Creative Direction Project Management Skills · Problem-Solving and Critical Thinking · Strategic Thinking · Presentation Skills · Continuous Learning and Adaptability · Product Vision Definition · Effective Communication · Complex Problem Solving · Planned and Systematic Execution

EDUCATION

IDC School of Design, IIT Bombay
Master of Design (Interaction Design)

NIT Tiruchirappalli

B.Tech (Computer Science & Engineering)

EXPERIENCE

Intuit, Bengaluru Jun 2024 - Present

Senior Product Designer

- Led multiple work streams inside the VEP team (Virtual Expert Platform) involving demand forecasting, capacity planning, allocation and ramp/supply procurement.
- As a platform team, which worked across verticals, I worked in influencing strategy and tech decisions, and Al inclusion, to drive teams towards a more cohesive system where the manual process and tribal knowledge of users is eliminated and users (or planners) can make confident decisions.
- Led team of 3 designers in making their design and decision making processes stronger. Also mentored them from time to time to uplift them professionally making them capable for industry.

Oracle Tech Hub, Bengaluru

Aug 2022 - Jun 2024

User Experience Designer

- Led various commercial projects on government and citizen facing applications which help in permitting, licensing, planning and code enforcement.
- Built synergies with cross-functional teams, of PM, developers and designers, across geographies to develop processes which reduced effort for efficient, timely and scalable results.
- Worked upon strategies to incorporate AI in future vision projects while handling projects independently and provided leadership and guidance to junior designers, fostering their professional growth and development.

D. E. Shaw India Private Limited

May 2021 - Jul 2021

Interaction Designer

- Contributed innovative ideas and solutions to address on a project which involved creating a roadmap planning and employee management application which would effectively reduce the errors while project estimations.
- Conducted user research, usability testing, and analysis to inform the design process and enhance the user experience.
- Created wireframes, prototypes, and user flows to visualize and iterate on design solutions, prioritizing usability and accessibility.

Cerner Corporation

Apr 2020 - Aug 2020

User Experience Designer

- Enabled physicians to dismiss/delete the AI proposed opportunities, a proposed documentation opportunity or clinical validation notification, presented by the NLP Engine of the system.
- Reduced the clicks by 33% while keeping actions least intrusive for the physician.
- Interfaced directly with clients to understand their design requirements, gather feedback, and address any concerns or revisions promptly.

People10 Technologies Inc.

May 2018 - Jun 2019

User Interface/Experience Designer

- Single handedly worked on developing an application for the Bomb squad to record and report details of the suspect package.
- Developed visually appealing and on-brand designs across various mediums including web, mobile, and print. There were 3 parts in here namely collaborator app, marketing website and branding.

Philips Healthcare

Jun 2016 - May 2018

UX Designer and Engineer

- I had the opportunity to work in 2 teams over here. In my first team I worked in the Health watch team where I contributed innovative ideas and solutions to address complex design challenges while handling creation of REST Microservices and their APIs for onboarding experiences.
- In my second team, I created wireframes, prototypes, and user flows to visualize while working on MRI dashboards which demanded adaptability and flexibility in widgets. I was also involved in development of this application using front end technologies like AngularJS, HTML, CSS

PUBLICATIONS

Exploration of inter-marker interactions in Tangible AR

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3562939.3565642

VRST '22: Proceedings of the 28th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology

- In this paper we explore multiple inter-marker interactions in the tangible AR space along with their use cases. We developed prototypes that demonstrate primarily five inter-marker interactions.

Grapho: Bringing line chart accessibility to the visually impaired

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3570211.3570213

IndiaHCI '22: Proceedings of the 13th Indian Conference on Human-Computer Interaction

- In this paper we propose Grapho, a graph visualization physical tool that allows a visually-impaired person to perceive, create and modify a line chart.

LEISURE

Badminton · Boardgames · Guitar · Playstation · Old music classics · Fiction · Al creations · Sketching · Concerts · Lakeside strolls